So, good morning. I know that you are excited for our Christmas play. I am excited for our
Christmas play. They have worked so hard. I do want to thank the parents. This is a crazy
season. If you have kids, you don't have kids. This is a crazy season. And so, to add play practice for
the past two months is a big commitment. So, thank you very much for that. They have done such a good
job. Just be praying for the kids as they're up there because it's you. This is scary. You guys are
scary. And so, they just need all of, I know that no matter what they do, you're going to think they're
the most amazing things in the whole world because they are. But they appreciate all your prayers. But
it's also the fourth Sunday of Advent. And so, I get to share with you, Pastor Ryan asked me if I
would share with you a little bit about my thoughts of how Jesus is our Prince of Peace because that is
the week that we are on. So, I will make it short because I know you just want to see the kids. But
I also am really excited to share with you a few things that God has been teaching me. And to be
honest, it's hard to find peace these days. It's hard to find peace politically. It's hard to find peace
within ourselves. It's hard to find peace within each other. There's just so much turmoil. It's so easy
to find something wrong with those around us rather than trying to make peace with them. So, if that's
the case, and Jesus is the Prince of Peace, and we're his followers, the question is, where is this peace
that he promised when the angels declared him coming that he is called over and over again? So, to answer
this, first, I want to look at one of the most common Scriptures used during the Christmas season, which
you will find in Isaiah 9, 6. And remember, this was written seven to eight hundred years before the birth
of Christ, yet it's the verse that we use often to describe Christ. It says,
for to us a child is born, to us a son is given, and the governor will be on his shoulders, and he will
be called Wonderful Counselor, Mighty God, Everlasting Father, Prince of Peace. So, let's look at what the
Hebrew, the original Hebrew word for that phrase, Prince of Peace, was. The original Hebrew word is
Sar Shalom. If you've ever watched The Chosen, you've heard the word Shalom. And you're probably
pretty familiar with what it means. But the word Sar means prince, or ruler, or leader. And Shalom,
yes, it means peace, but it doesn't mean the type of peace like war and peace that we're thinking.
It means wholeness, completeness, well-being. So, in Isaiah, this Prince of Peace, it literally means
the ruler of wholeness, or completeness. Fast forward roughly 750 years, and we get another
very popular verse that we talk about on Christmas. Luke 2, 10 through 14. It says,
but the angel said to them, do not be afraid. I bring you good news that will cause great joy
for all people. Today, in the town of David, a Savior has been born to you. He is the Messiah,
the Lord. This will be a sign to you. You will find the baby wrapped in clothes and lying in a manger.
Suddenly, a great company of heavenly hosts appeared with the angel, praising God and saying,
glory to God in the highest heaven, and on earth, peace to those that rest, that whom his favor rests.
This is the same Hebrew word that Isaiah uses to describe the coming Messiah. They are saying that
Jesus has brought wholeness to that which is broken. That's the peace that Jesus brought. So, what is it that
was broken that Jesus brought wholeness or that Jesus put back together in completeness? We have to go back
to the very beginning in Genesis. So, in our kids' classes, if you were here when Sandra Richter, Dr. Sandra Richter,
gave her message. She talks about how the Old Testament connects to the New Testament, which sounds silly,
right? But like the big overarching connection. And so, we've been working on that for the past three
months in our kids' classes. We call it now, not the Old Testament and the New Testament, but the Old
Promise and the New Promise, because that's what's happening. In the Old Testament, we see how life was
intended in Eden, right? We look at what Eden was like with Adam and Eve and how things were intended
to be. We see that they lived with God. They walked with God. There was no fear. There was no anxiety.
Nobody had selfishness because God was with them, right? That's how it was intended to be. God's original
intent for humanity was for the people of God to dwell in the place of God with full access to the
presence of God. That's how we were meant to live. But you know the story, right? Adam and Eve chose their
own selfish desires. They chose Satan over God. And in that moment, that separation began because God is
perfect and he cannot dwell with sin. Isaiah 59 2 says, your iniquities have separated you from God.
Your sins have hidden your face from him. So humans start experiencing the brokenness of God. They have
that separation. We're no longer walking with God. That's what was broken. And we spend the whole Old
Testament living in that broken world, right? We see wars. We see hardship. We see the earth get to the
point where God floods all of it because it's, there's so much destruction in it because we are living in a
broken world apart from God. But as soon as that sin enters the world, God has a plan immediately. The
Bible tells it that, that, um, yes, Satan will bite the heel of the Messiah, but the Messiah will crush his
head. He has a plan. And throughout the whole Testament, he's laying out that plan for us through promises,
promises, which is why it's the old promise. One of those promises is made to Noah. So you know the
story, there's a big flood. He promises Noah to never again give humanity what it deserves. And in order
for us to remember that promise, he gives us a rainbow. But the original word for a rainbow is
actually a war bow. I like to show this picture, um, to my class. Do you have it, Dave?
There's a picture of a rainbow. It's really cool too. Um, it's the, it's the, so a rainbow is an arch,
right? Just like a war bow, a war, like a bow and arrow. It's the arch, but God lays his weapon of
destruction down, right? He puts it down. So when you look at a rainbow, if it's a bow and arrow,
it's shaped like this. That, there it is. I told you it was a cool picture. So if the arrow is going to
be shot, which direction is it facing? Heaven, right? It's God's way of saying, I will never
again give you what you deserve. I will take the punishment that you deserve. That arrow is facing
up. Every time we see a rainbow, we're reminded of one of the first promises that God made with man
saying, you deserve destruction. I'm going to take that from you. And then we have a promise that he made
to Abraham in Genesis 15. The promise that he made to Abraham is really weird. If you know anything
about the Bible in this, then you know that there is a near Eastern ritual that Abraham would have been
very familiar with, that two parties would use to make a covenant. Now when we buy a house or like we do
a war treaty, we like write stuff down. They did it a little different back then. God told, so God promised
Abraham that the Messiah would come from his lineage, that he would be the father of many nations. Abraham
had no children. And so he says to God, how do I know that this is really going to happen? And God
says, let's make a covenant. So what he does is he tells him, I need you to get three animals. I need
you to get a ram, a goat, and a heifer, and I need you to cut them in half. Then I need you to get a
turtle dove and a pigeon, and I need you to sacrifice them, but don't cut them in half. So then he takes,
he says, take the ram, the goat, and the heifer, lay half of their body on this side, lay half of their
body on that side, and let the blood drain into the middle. Super weird, right? And then we got a pigeon
on one side, turtle dove on the other. Then he says, well, so Abraham at this time, he knew this was a
covenant. He knew that they were going to do this because this was common. And the point of it is
both parties of the covenant walked down the center on the blood. And this is saying, we are taking this
so seriously that if either of us breaks our side of the covenant, may our body be like that of these
animals. That's a serious covenant. Guarantee you, we would make our house payments if our body was going
to be like that of one of these animals, right? That paper would mean a lot more than it did.
And so Abraham knew, but Abraham's side of the covenant was that he was supposed to obey God.
Have any of us fully successfully obeyed God our entire lives? No. Can you imagine how nervous he
was? He's going to make a covenant with God and he's going to be like one of these animals if he makes,
if he breaks it. But God puts Abraham into a deep sleep, if you know this story. And during this deep
sleep, Abraham has a vision of a flaming pot and a flaming torch and a smoking pot. That's what goes
down the center of this covenant. That's God. God is the only one that takes this covenant because he
knows Abraham will fail. And so what Abraham knows this means is if you fail, I will take your punishment.
That is the promise that God makes throughout the Old Testament. Fast forward roughly 2,000 years to a
baby born in a dingy, cold stable. No electricity, no heat, pain, hardship, embarrassment. Jesus leaves all the
comforts of the comforts of heaven to come to this earth. The angels call him the Prince of Peace
or Sharsalong because he fixed what was broken in his birth. See, we needed a sacrifice, right? We deserved it,
but we needed a perfect sacrifice. Jesus fulfilled the old promise in the new promise that we have in the
New Testament with his birth. He gives us a peace that is complete like we had in Eden because we are no longer
separated from God. When Jesus sacrifices his blood and takes our sin to that cross, we are no longer
separated from God like we used to be when we were separated from Eden. He died so that we can
experience him now. This is the peace that Christmas brings. Isaiah 53, 5 says he was wounded for our
transgressions. He was bruised for our iniquities. The chastisement for our peace was upon him and by
his stripes we are healed. Remember, this was written 750 years before Jesus was born. Jesus fulfilled
over 300 prophecies. If you're like me and you love going down the rabbit hole of proof, you like to see
all the connections and the things that we can prove through history, you look at the fact that over 300
prophecies were fulfilled in the life of Jesus. You can't, that can't be a coincidence. Some of them
that are very popular is Jesus was born in Bethlehem. He was born of a virgin. He was born in the line of
David. He was pierced through the crucifixion. He was betrayed for 30 pieces of silver. He was silent
before his accusers and he was buried with the rich. Knowing this, knowing that the Lamb of God broke the
curse and brought back completeness or wholeness and is our prince of peace, you also can have that
peace that passes understanding because it's not a peace that the world gave you and it's not a peace
that the world can take away. In thinking about this today, when you think about the fact that that
promise was fulfilled, he completed that and one day we will again be with him in Eden.
This Christmas, reflect on that when you think about what your relationships are with God. Number one,
do you really trust him? Are you really giving him whatever situation that you're in right now
that is causing you anxiety or worry or fear? Do you trust that the King of Kings and the Lord of Lords
and the Prince of Peace completed the promise that he gave us and he lives in you and he works out all
things for good of those that love the Lord? Do you trust him? You will keep in perfect peace
those whose minds are steadfast because they trust in you. Isaiah 23, 6. Are you allowing him to keep
your mind steadfast because of your trust in him? What about your internal peace? Do you grasp how
loved you are by God? When challenges come, things get scary, do you go back and think about the reminder
that God will never leave you or forsake you? Philippians 4, 6 through 7, do not be anxious about
anything but in every situation, by prayer and petition with thanksgiving, present your request to God
and the peace of God that transcends all understanding will guard your hearts and mind. Are you letting him
provide that peace that we so desperately need in this world? Not worldly peace. Obviously, that's failed.
We all know that. But God created a peace that is in completeness and wholeness. And then finally,
peace with those around you. I can't tell you how much a relationship that is shattered ruins your peace.
It ruins my peace. It's in the back of my mind all the time. Are you allowing the fact that God completed
what he promised to shape your relationships? Romans 12, 18 says, if it is possible, as far as it depends on you,
live at peace with anyone. Don't let it steal your peace. It's not worth it. Try to look at the other person's
point of view. Put yourself in their shoes and go back at that situation and see if there's any way
you can create peace with that person so that the world doesn't steal your peace. Finally, as I was working
on this message, trying to do it all in my own strength, which is typically what I do, I felt God
nagging on me saying, let me talk to you. Let me talk to you. But that's, this can be scary, right?
This is important. I got to do it. And he just kept saying it. Well, because God loves me so much.
My computer froze. Like I was going down rabbit holes and completely froze. Like control, alt,
delete, nothing worked. I could not get anything on my computer to work. And he was like, he was saying,
I said, let me talk to you. So I put my computer down and got out my Bible. Shocking, right?
And he brought me and I said, okay, I'm going to trust you. I want you to talk to me. And he,
he brought me back to Isaiah 9, 6, but he told me, read before it. So this is what I want. This is what,
he wanted me to share. And I want to share with you. This is what the birth of Jesus really brings
to us. Isaiah 9, 2 says, the people walking in darkness have seen a great light. On those living
in the lands of deep darkness, a light has dawned. You have enlarged the nation and increased their joy.
They rejoice before you as people rejoice at a harvest, as warriors rejoice when dividing the plunder.
For as in the day of the many in defeat, you have shattered the yoke that burdens them.
The bar across their shoulders, the rod of their oppressors. How many of you feel like you have a bar
weighing you down across your shoulders? God has shattered that. Every warrior's boot used in battle
and every garment rolled in blood will be destined for burning. It will be fuel for the fire. For to us,
a child is born. To us, a son is given. And the governor will be on his shoulders and he will be
called mighty God, wonderful counselor, mighty God, everlasting father, prince of peace. Are you allowing
him in the completeness, knowing the insider information that he already completed the promise
that he made us? Are you allowing him to shatter the yoke that drags you down? Don't look for the world
for peace because it didn't give it to you in the first place and it can't take it away. Focus on Jesus
and the prince of peace this holiday season. Let's pray. Heavenly Father, we will never have words to thank you for
leaving the comforts of heaven and coming to this earth as a baby to sacrifice your life for us, to take what we deserve
with your blood and your sacrifice. Jesus, thank you for that. And I pray that everyone in this room will be able to remember
that when anxiety hits and things aren't going the way we want it to go, that we know that you already won. You already
broke the curse that held us down. God, help us lean on you this Christmas season and allow the peace that you want to
give us to overwhelm us. God, I pray that you would be with every child that is behind me that is getting ready to
perform. Overwhelm them with your peace, a peace that doesn't make any sense, that passes
understanding. Wrap your arms around them and let them know that they are so loved and
there's nothing that they could do today that would make them any more love. Jesus, we thank you for this church
and for these people. In your name I pray. Amen.
Amen.
The children of Israel were waiting for a savior.
For hundreds of years, the prophets spoke of the Messiah.
Men like Isaiah proclaimed him to be the wonderful counselor.
The mighty God.
And the prince of.
The prince of peace, the prophets of God, spoke of the child, report of Bethlehem.
The prophecies.
The prophecies brought hope to people who lived in captivity.
But for hundreds of years, the voices.
The voices fell silent.
Excuse me, just one moment.
Hey!
Who is out there making all that racket?
Are you yelling at me?
Are you the one making all that noise?
Well, I am a carpenter.
This is my carpenter shop.
You're not a carpenter, you're Joe the church maintenance guy.
I'm also Joe the aspiring actor.
You are?
I am.
Do you want to see my headshots?
Why are you making all that noise?
Well, I'm playing just with the carpenter, right?
And carpenter's got carpents.
What are you saying?
I'm not sure that's even a word.
Plus, we have some cabinets backstage that need repairs.
So since I'm playing carpenter, I figured I just killed two birds with one stone.
Yes, both power gels and table saws.
Is there a better way to carpenter's?
Not in the New Testament.
They didn't have electricity.
Joseph couldn't just plug in a table saw whenever he wanted to.
Neither do I.
It's all cordless.
Listen, Joe, we're trying to tell the story of the first Christmas out here.
I know.
And it's super hard to do so when I have to yell over power gels and table saws.
Oh, I get what you're saying now.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
No more power gels doing the show.
I got it.
Thank you.
Just hammering.
No, no, no.
No hammering.
Do they not have hammers in the New Testament?
No, they had hammers.
It just would be easier if you wait until after the show.
To...
To hammer.
Sure.
Okay, I got it.
I'll stop hammering for now.
Thank you.
Please go wait for your cue.
Oh.
Yes, ma'am.
Wait, can I use a screwdriver, though?
If it's quiet.
Okay.
After many years without a word from heaven, the silence was finally broken.
Sorry.
Sorry about that.
I wasn't looking where I was going.
I'm going to clean this up later.
A young woman named Mary received a visitor from heaven.
The angel said to Mary,
Do not be afraid, but I bring you good news.
You have a son, and you will name him Jesus.
You will be the savior of his people.
Mary was overjoyed, and she said to the angel,
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Time out.
Uh, that's not what she said.
I know it's not the line, but I have a question about something in this scene.
Right now?
Yes, right now.
I mean, this isn't exactly the best time.
I mean, we're actually performing in front of all these people.
I know we are, but it's just not the only thing that's happening.
I mean, here I am, a young girl, and all of a sudden, I'm pregnant.
Yeah.
And I'm just supposed to be happy about that.
Why wouldn't you?
Why wouldn't you be?
Your child is the Son of God.
You know that.
I know that.
But do you think all the people in this tiny little town know that?
Well, I...
The angel didn't tell everyone, didn't she?
Just you.
Just you so far.
You know the kind of people we have in this town.
They love the gossip.
And we're just out.
That sweet little Mary, who hasn't even gotten married yet, is having her baby.
I suppose that could make life difficult for you.
Well, it don't make life difficult, all right?
What am I going to tell my mother?
And what about Joseph?
Oh, you don't have to worry about Joseph.
I don't.
The angel's going to tell him as well.
Whoa, did I just hear that, Angel Roy?
My fiancé's going to have a baby?
Yes, you did.
I can't believe this.
Did you know this was happening?
Actually, I just found out myself.
Is the angel going to tell everyone in this tiny town?
I mean, you know the kind of people we have around here?
Yes, Mary was just telling me.
Boy, I thought things were messy backstage.
Mary, Joseph, I know this isn't exactly what you thought would happen when you first met,
but God chose you for this special purpose.
And God's plans are never easy.
There's a point.
Think about Noah.
That guy spent 40 days and nights in a floating suit.
And that's just while it was raining.
He was on that boat much longer than that.
But he got through it.
It's all family.
I guess that means we'll do this mess ourselves.
Right?
I think we'll do just fine.
God would have chosen you if you didn't have a plan.
That's right, Mary.
That's right.
Mary, just think.
Someday we'll look back and we'll ask the question.
Mary, did you know?
Whoa!
What?
What's the matter?
That's a great song.
We're about to kick off, but that's what we call copyright material.
Sorry.
It's okay.
I think if we get creative, we'll pull up with something all on our own.
Dancing to the earth, through the important things you said, to Nazareth I go, flying all the way.
Mary, did you know you will have a son?
He will be the Prince of Peace and he will call you Mom.
Oh, don't be afraid, don't be afraid, you are highly favored.
You are going to have a son and he will be your savior.
Don't be afraid, don't be afraid, you are highly favored.
Stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe, stay safe.
Well, that's a great song for Mary, but what about one for me?
Why not?
Hey, angels!
Oh, carpenter of Nazareth, whose wedding day is nigh.
An angel came to visit you, an angel from on high.
God has a plan for you and the woman you will wear.
God's son will soon be born to her and he will call you Dad.
Stay safe.
How was that?
Not bad, not bad.
But you know you just can't be the classics.
You're right.
Come on, kids.
Let's wrap this part of the story up with a song of real hope.
Just a tiny, no room and this is where the greatest story ever told begins.
With just a tiny beating heart, it'll create a song of real hope.
And this is where the greatest story ever told begins.
With just a tiny beating heart, it'll create a meaning in.
It's where a star led to a stable, a baby's crying made angels sing.
And this earth to find a savior led to heaven's humble king.
Where the wise men found the angels, the shepherds found the lamb.
And death found my Emmanuel, cause the Bethlehem.
Love is born, hope is near.
Heaven's light has made the darkness disappear.
Peace on earth, good will to man.
God with us, all because of Bethlehem.
And the child in a cradle, took him upon a cross.
He knew the role was leading him to pay a praise to God.
When no other arms could carry the weight of all our sins.
He took the fall and it happened all because of Bethlehem.
Love is born, hope is near.
Heaven's light has made the darkness disappear.
Peace on earth, good will to man.
God with us, all because of Bethlehem.
Love is born, good will to man.
From a dream of love left empty, to a father's right and wrong.
God with us, all because of Bethlehem.
Mary and Joseph were married quietly, and the young couple did everything they could to
prepare for the birth of their son.
There's a lot of work to do, but together they made preparations to become a family of three,
welcoming the Son of God to the world.
It's all ready, Mary, we have a nursery built for the boy, a crib where he can sleep,
a playboy where he can play, and a rocking chair.
Where he can rock?
No, that's where you're going to sleep when the baby finally lies down.
You thought of everything.
Yep, this house is ready for a baby.
Just in time, I think this baby is ready to be born.
Everything's going perfectly according to plan, and nothing can mess this up.
Then things got messed up!
What?
There came a decree from Caesar.
Caesar, who is Caesar?
Is he the salad maker?
The great Caesar Augustus decided to take a census of all the people in his empire.
But in order to conduct the census, everyone had to go back to their hometown.
But this is our hometown.
Actually, Mary, this isn't my hometown.
You're not from Nazareth?
Bethlehem High School, class of 3 BC.
Go Eagles!
Bethlehem?
We have to go to Bethlehem?
I'm nine months pregnant.
I'm sure we'll get back before the baby comes.
This all happened according to the prophet Micah.
Who declared the child being born in Bethlehem?
Like I said, Go Eagles!
Mary Joseph traveled to Bethlehem.
I'm not having the baby on the open road, Joseph.
Don't worry, Mary.
As soon as we get to Bethlehem, we'll get a room and a hotel.
But there are no rooms anywhere for rent!
No rooms?
No rooms.
Nothing in the Holiday Inn?
No.
The Comfort Inn?
What about the Dew Drop Inn?
Not a one.
We were just full of good news today.
But there is a kind inkiever who offered them a solution.
Thank goodness.
He offered Mary and Justice a chance to stay in the only room he had available.
Yay!
In a stable.
What?
A stable full of animals.
Joe?
Yeah, Mary?
This is not how I wanted to have our baby.
That makes two of us.
Are you sure we have to do this?
Sorry.
This is the place.
Where's the baby gonna sleep?
In the manger, of course.
In the fridge for the animals.
It's just the right size.
And what about Mary?
Looks like I'm sleeping on the straw.
Oh, Mary.
I'm really sorry about this.
Joseph, it's okay.
We're together, you and I.
And soon the baby will make three.
This is no place to have a baby.
Especially not the Son of God.
Joseph, maybe God wants it this way.
Our son will know what it's like to have hardship.
To have disappointment.
To be human.
He doesn't deserve that, though.
But maybe he wants to know what it is to be human.
To have nothing.
To suffer hardship.
And sleep in a noisy barn full of animals.
He's gonna get an earful tonight.
Definitely not gonna be a noisy night.
Or a silent night.
And with that, cue the music.
Noisy night.
Very loud night.
Nothing's wrong.
That's not right.
There's no way you will gently sleep.
As you listen to the fleeting sheep.
Not so silent tonight.
Noisy night.
Very loud night.
That was so blue.
That was so nice.
There's so warm in the morning.
Not you.
How about the pig?
Not bad.
That sounded pretty good.
How about you, chicken?
Well, that's a talented chicken.
Thank you.
Hey, wait a minute.
How about you, cow?
Go ahead, cow.
Give him a nice bath.
I think the cow is messing with us.
Let's just get this story going before the chicken makes me sick.
Fair enough.
The shepherds were in the field watching their sheep.
Bah!
When all of a sudden, an angel appeared.
People!
Bah!
Oh, look!
An angel!
Yes, I am!
An angel of the Lord.
Here to tell you good news for all the world.
Unto you is born this day in the city of David a Savior, who is Christ the Lord.
And this will be a sign unto you.
You will find the baby wrapped in swaddling clothes and lying in a manger.
A manger?
You mean like an animal feeding child?
What, are they in a stable or something?
Yes!
Well, okay then.
But why are you here telling us?
Yeah, yeah.
Shouldn't you be telling the king or something?
Oh, the king will find out soon enough.
But this news isn't just for the rich and faithful.
It's for everyone.
Jesus has come, and he's come to be the savior of all.
All meaning all?
All meaning all.
Even shepherds?
Even shepherds.
All of a sudden a whole host of angels arrive singing.
Glory to God in the highest and peace on earth!
Hey, angel.
We heard the lady.
She said you were going to sing something.
Oh, all right.
Come on, fellow angels.
Let's sing our hearts out on this one.
And this time, the right word.
Oh boy, I do love this song.
Hey Angel, we heard the lady. She said you were gonna sing something. Oh, alright. Come on, fellow angels. Let's sing our hearts out on this one. And this time, the right word. Oh boy, I do love this song.
While shepherds kept there watching for silent flocks by night. People throughout the heavens, they show the holy light.
Go tell it on the mountain, over the hills and everywhere. Go tell it on the mountain that Jesus Christ is born. Go tell it, go, go tell it. Go tell it, go, go tell it.
The shepherds feared and trembled. The world above the earth. Bring out the angel chorus that hailed our Savior's birth.
Go tell it on the mountain, over the hills and everywhere. Go tell it on the mountain.
That Jesus Christ is born. Go tell it, go, go tell it. Go tell it, go, go tell it.
Down in the lonely manger, the humble Christ was born. And God sent our salvation, that blessed Christmas, Lord.
Go tell it, go, go tell it on the mountain, over the hills and everywhere. Go tell it on the mountain.
That Jesus Christ is born. That Jesus Christ is born. Go tell it, go, go tell it. Go tell it, go, go tell it.
On the mountain that Jesus Christ is home.
Go, tell it, go, go, tell it.
Oh, Mary, this has been quite the adventure.
It certainly has.
We showered all the way from Nazareth to Bethlehem.
Such a long journey.
Slept in a stable full of animals.
We're still sleeping with the animals.
We came a family.
Our sweet baby boy.
Some angels told a bunch of shepherds.
One of them brought a drum.
What's that?
The shepherd boy with the drum?
The who?
The little drummer boy?
Oh, yeah, I almost forgot about him.
Ooh, can we sing a song?
Sorry, Joseph.
That's under copyright as well.
Thanks.
What about the one with the wise men?
Of course.
We three kings, we can sing that one, right?
They were here after all.
They brought gifts for the baby.
Gold, frankincense, and myrrh.
It's only right we sing about them.
Let's do it.
A one, a two, and a one, two, three.
Stop right there, Joseph.
Not so fast.
You two need to pack any quick.
We do.
Don't you remember what the angel told you in your dream
after the wise men left?
Angel?
Oh, no, I almost forgot.
Joseph, you must pack up everything and flee to Egypt.
Why?
It's King Herod.
The wise men told him about Jesus before they came to see you.
Herod is very jealous to hear that a new king has been born in his kingdom,
and if you don't go away now, he's going to kill a child.
No!
Go to Egypt!
Protect your family!
Protect our son!
Well, I didn't see that plot twist coming.
Oh, Joseph, will this ever end, bro?
We've been through so much.
I know.
Is it ever going to get any easier?
I wish I could tell you it gets easier, but the road ahead will always be challenging,
especially for Jesus.
You mean he's going to face hardships like these?
More than you can imagine.
Way more than he wants to still be.
Why would God do this to him?
To his own son.
He could have made a better plan.
Don't you guys see it yet?
It was always a plan.
Jesus will learn everything there is to know about being human.
No pain, no suffering, no experience, heartbreak, betrayal, all things that make life difficult.
We've trusted God so far, we need to keep trusting him.
You're right.
Let's get our face and head to Egypt.
Hey, quiet!
How about a little traveling music for the road?
Right up!
Away from the danger, the family must go.
An angel brought warnings to Mary and Joe.
In Egypt you'll slumber until it is safe.
Then back home to Nazareth your future awaits.
He knows our good times, he knows all the bad.
Jesus, my Savior of this, I am glad.
It never was easy, there's no silent night.
You suffered and saved us, you gave us the light.
Be near me, Lord Jesus, I ask you to stay.
Close by me forever and love me, I pray.
Bless all the dear children in thy tender care.
And bid us for heaven to live with you there.
Mary and Joseph led to Egypt, fulfilling the prophecy of Hosea who wrote, "Out of Egypt I called my son."
Just like the Israelites in Genesis and Exodus, they lived as refugees.
And when King Herod died--
Hold on there, Mary, lady, hold on just a moment.
Who are you guys?
Who do we look like?
We're the wise men.
Oh, the wise men!
You're saying, Lord, too late.
Too late?
We don't get to talk about the star.
We don't get to present our gifts of gold, frankincense, and mint.
We don't get to go home by another route so we can avoid telling Herod where the baby Jesus is.
I'm sorry.
We're actually almost out of time.
Well, that's awfully disappointing.
Kind of.
It's kind of been the thing today.
What do you mean?
I mean, as exciting as the birth of Jesus is for us, it was a pretty big disruption for Mary and Joseph.
They had plans with their own poor family.
Then an angel showed up and told them we're going to be parents to the Son of God.
Wow, but God made things easy for them, right?
Hardly, they had a trouble far from home and stayed in a stable full of noisy animals.
When the baby was born, they were visited by shepherds.
And then you guys, of course.
Of course.
And then they had to flee to Egypt so the king Herod could not hurt the baby Jesus.
That Herod, I told you guys, he was bad news.
The sad thing is, most of the time we don't even notice how hard life was for Mary and Joseph.
We just see the mom and the dad and the baby in the stable surrounded by sleeping animals and takes off at a silent night.
Let me tell you, neighborhood lady, I've slept in a stable before, that's never a silent night.
If you're spending time with those animals, I believe you.
But look at it this way.
All the herdship Jesus and his family did, it served a purpose.
By the time Jesus was a grown man ready to start his ministry, he knew what it meant to be human.
He knew pain.
He knew heartbreak.
He knows everything we do about living in this hard world.
That's exactly the way I saw the last scene.
Wow, we really did miss everything.
Not everything.
You're here just in time for the big finale.
You mean we get to sing?
Sure, why not?
Do you also get to wish everyone a Merry Christmas?
Absolutely.
Can we also leave them with one more thought?
Can we let everyone know that we can go to Jesus with all our troubles?
Because Jesus definitely knew what trouble was like.
Want to know something?
I think you already did.
Come on boys, let you move real bang.
How about, Mary, did you know?
Nope.
Very disgusting, Ellen.
It's under copyright.
Okay then.
The Little Drummer Boy.
Also under copyright.
What about It's Christmas?
We can do that one.
What if you want?
It's Christmases.
Come on everybody.
Shepherds, Mary, animals, angels, Joseph, everyone.
Let's end this one on a high note.
We're gonna dance with our hands, celebrate.
It's Christmas.
Light up the world.
Jesus is born for woe.
Raise your voice.
Make some noise.
It's Christmas.
Let's celebrate and shout for joy.
It's the reason why we sing and why we celebrate.
It's Christmas time.
Yeah, it's Christmas time.
It's the season that he's given us a gift so great.
It's Christmas time.
Yeah, it's Christmas time.
He's the light of the world.
Come down to us.
From heaven, now everyone sing.
We're gonna dance with our hands, celebrate.
It's Christmas.
Light up the world.
Jesus is born for woe.
Raise your voice.
Make some noise.
It's Christmas.
Let's celebrate and shout for joy.
The reason why we sing and why we celebrate.
It's Christmas time.
Yeah, it's Christmas time.
It's the season that he's given us a gift so great.
It's Christmas time.
Yeah, it's Christmas time.
He's the light of the world.
Come down to us.
From heaven, now everyone sing.
We're gonna dance with our hands, celebrate.
It's Christmas.
Light up the world.
Jesus is born for woe.
Raise your voice.
Make some noise.
It's Christmas.
Let's celebrate and shout for joy.
Everybody sing with us.
It's Christmas.
Yeah, throw your hands up in the air and shout for joy.
Everybody sing with us.
It's Christmas.
Yeah, throw your hands up in the air and shout for joy.
Everybody sing with us.
It's Christmas.
Yeah, throw your hands up in the air and shout for joy.
We're gonna dance with our hands.
Celebrate.
It's Christmas.
Light on the world.
Jesus is born.
Whoa.
Raise your voice.
Make some noise.
It's Christmas.
Let's celebrate and shout for joy.
Everybody sing with us.
Yeah, throw your hands up in the air and shout for joy.
It's Christmas.
Everybody sing with us.
Yeah, throw your hands up in the air and shout for joy.
It's Christmas.
Everybody sing with us.
Yeah, throw your hands up in the air and shout for joy.
You know, we could've seen We Three Kings.
What?
Oh, man.
Thank you.
They did amazing.
I am so singing proud of them.
Thank you guys so much for coming.
That was our Christmas play.
Give them a few minutes.
They're going to head back to their rooms and you can go pick them up there.
But if you see one of these kids out there, please tell them they did a great job.
We had a lot of hiccups and they did amazing.
So thank you so much for coming and Merry Christmas.
We're rocking around Christmas tree.
We're going to have a lot of hiccups and we're going to have a lot of hiccups and we're going to have a lot of hiccups and we're going to have a lot of hiccups and we're going to have a lot of hiccups and we're going to have a lot of hiccups and we're going to have a lot of hiccups and we're going to have a lot of hiccups and we're going to have a lot of hiccups and we're going to have a lot of hiccups and we're going to have a lot of hiccups and we're going to have a lot of hiccups.
We're going to have a lot of hiccups.